

DATA SCIENTIST · BIOINFORMATICS SPECIALIST

New York City, NY

🛮 +814-996-9078 | 🗷 sansanlin85@gmail.com | 🎁 teresa-sansan.github.io/ | 🖸 teresa-sansan | 🛅 teresa-jui-shan-lin

Summary _

I am an enthusiastic data scientist specializing in data engineering, machine learning, and pipeline building using Python and R. With 3+ years of experience, I am actively seeking opportunities that will allow me to leverage my expertise and analytical skills to drive meaningful insights and outcomes.

Experience _____

Data Science Associate NYC, NY

New York Genome Center

May 2021 - Present

- · Improving PRS cross-ancestral transferability using cell-type specific functional annotations trained by deep learning models
- QC and integrating on WGS genotype and phenotype files from 17k individuals.
- · Implement pipeline for functional fine-mapping

Research Assistant State College, PA

THE PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY (ADVISOR: DR. YIFEI HUANG)

- Thesis: Supervised Variant Prioritization and Its Evaluation
- Build a machine learning pipeline mainly with python for variant prioritization, especially in missense mutation
- Maximize the performance by comparing different statistical learning methods (i.e., logistic regression, SVM, and gradient boosting)

Research Assistant Tainan, Taiwan

NATIONAL CHENG KUNG UNIVERSITY (ADVISOR: DR. JAN-JONG HUANG)

Mar 2017 - Feb 2019

Aug 2019 - Mar 2021

- Study the influence of lung cancer cell on leukocyte transformation
- Use in vivo and in vitro assays to investigate p53-mediated micro-environment in lung cancer progressionn
- Observe the mobility of M2-like macrophage in conditioned medium of lung cancer cell

Education

M.S. in Bioinformatics and Genomics

State College, PA

THE PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY

Aug. 2019 - May. 2021

B.S. in Biotechnology and Bioindustry Sciences

Tainan, Taiwan

NATIONAL CHENG KUNG UNIVERSITY

Sep. 2015 - May. 2019

Skills_

Programming Language/Tools Python, R, Linux/Unix, Git, LeTeX, Conda **Machine Learning Package** Scikit learn, Pytorch, TensorFlow

Bioinformatics PLINK, Variant Prioritization, Fine-mapping, IGV, STARR, SAMtools

Others Pipeline building, Data Engineering, Data Visualization

Honors & Awards

2019	Dean's List, National Cheng Kung University	Tainan, Taiwan
2017	Dean's List , National Cheng Kung University	Tainan, Taiwan
2017	Department representative, Shenh Long Bio-Tech International Co., LTD	Long An, Vietnam
2016	Taiwan representative, Japan-Asia Youth academic exchange	Osaka, Japan
2016	Dean's List , National Cheng Kung University	Tainan, Taiwan

MARCH 2, 2023 JUISHAN TERESA LIN 1